<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Reporting | Goiardi]]></title>
  <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/categories/reporting/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-21T23:09:46-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jeremy Bingham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goiardi Version 0.5.1 - Rodan Overhead]]></title>
    <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/05/26/goiardi-version-0-dot-5-1-rodan-overhead/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-26T11:04:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/05/26/goiardi-version-0-dot-5-1-rodan-overhead</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The sky darkens. Blotting out the sun, Rodan appears to destroy beloved landmarks and stomp on small models of tanks. Goiardi <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/releases/tag/v0.5.1">version 0.5.1</a> has been released.</p>

<p>This is an incremental release, made up of bug fixes and relatively minor new features. The most interesting new features are <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/tree/cc9aeb1766be7515458dcc6ad6e5260201b0e837#event-logging">event logging</a> and <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/tree/cc9aeb1766be7515458dcc6ad6e5260201b0e837#reporting">reporting</a>, although the log level changes are also nice.</p>

<p>From the CHANGELOG:</p>

<ul>
<li>Add log levels (from debug to critical). This makes -V/&mdash;verbose useful.</li>
<li>Add an easier option in the config file to specify log levels by name.</li>
<li>ipv6 already worked, but accidentally. Now it works in a more deliberate
fashion, preventing mishaps with addresses, colons, and port numbers.</li>
<li>Authentication protocol version 1.1 now supported.</li>
<li>Remove a sort on run lists that was there for some reason. I have no idea
what it was put there for, but it was wrong.</li>
<li>Add an event log to log changes to objects like nodes, clients, etc. See the
README or godocs for details.</li>
<li>Add support for reporting (<a href="http://docs.opscode.com/reporting.html"><a href="http://docs.opscode.com/reporting.html">http://docs.opscode.com/reporting.html</a></a>)</li>
</ul>


<p>This release should not break old save files, if you&rsquo;re using that. If you&rsquo;re using MySQL, you&rsquo;ll need to deploy the sqitch changes.</p>

<p>The next big things to start working on are the long promised Postgres support, and etcd/serf/consul etc. integration. Groupcache has also been asked for and looks like a worthwhile thing to pick up. As always, the <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/issues?state=open">issues page</a> is a good place to look at what&rsquo;s being worked on.</p>

<p>Goiardi is also starting to grow beyond using chef-pedant for most of its testing; it&rsquo;s about time to start more native golang tests for goiardi and not use chef-pedant for the main tests. It should always work with chef-pedant, of course, but goiardi&rsquo;s starting to get more features that chef-pedant doesn&rsquo;t check.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
