<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Fixes | Goiardi]]></title>
  <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/categories/fixes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-12T09:33:16-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jeremy Bingham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goiardi Version 0.8.2 - Can-shaped Cranberry Sauce]]></title>
    <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/11/23/goiardi-version-0-dot-8-2-can-shaped-cranberry-sauce/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-23T11:29:27-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/11/23/goiardi-version-0-dot-8-2-can-shaped-cranberry-sauce</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a minor release fixing a couple of small issues that popped up that seemed important enough that they probably shouldn&rsquo;t wait until 1.0.0 comes out.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/releases/tag/v0.8.2">Goiardi version 0.8.2</a> fixes a couple of typos, one with checking errors when checking for the existence of a client in SQL mode, and one for the option to use postgres in the sample config file. The <code>use-postgresql</code> option was documented correctly elsewhere, but was listed incorrectly as <code>use-postgres</code> in the sample config file. This release also adds some checks to make sure the directory given for the local filestore exists, and is a directory.</p>

<p>Binaries are up on the release page, as usual.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Goiardi Version 0.8.1 and Schob Version 0.1.1 - Hand of Ishtar, Hand of Nergal]]></title>
    <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/10/15/goiardi-version-0-dot-8-1-and-schob-version-0-dot-1-1-hand-of-ishtar-hand-of-nergal/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-15T13:17:58-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/10/15/goiardi-version-0-dot-8-1-and-schob-version-0-dot-1-1-hand-of-ishtar-hand-of-nergal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In ancient Mesopotamia, diseases were often referred to as being the &ldquo;hand&rdquo; of some god. The hand of Nergal was a plague of some kind, while the hand of Ishtar was some kind of STD. Ishtar is generally identified with the Greek Aphrodite and Roman Venus as a goddess of love (although she was by no means identical to Aphrodite and Venus), so the name&rsquo;s quite appropriate. The word &ldquo;venereal&rdquo; ultimately derives from &ldquo;Venus&rdquo;, after all.</p>

<p>These are two minor releases. <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/releases/tag/v0.8.1">Goiardi version 0.8.1</a> moves the bulk of the documentation from the README to <a href="http://goiardi.readthedocs.org/en/latest/index.html">readthedocs</a>, where it should be much easier to read and work on, fixes a small issue with the postgres SQL dump file, and disables SSLv3. <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/schob/releases/tag/v0.1.1">Schob 0.1.1</a>  adds a fix to allow building schob on 32 bit platforms and on Windows, and updates links to the goiardi shovey documentation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
