<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Authentication | Goiardi]]></title>
  <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/categories/authentication/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-08T00:33:13-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jeremy Bingham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Version 0.4.0 of Goiardi Released. Now, With Authentication!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/03/16/version-0-dot-4-0-of-goiardi-released/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-16T10:28:50-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/03/16/version-0-dot-4-0-of-goiardi-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A new version of goiardi, <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/releases/tag/v0.4.0">version 0.4.0</a>, as been released.</p>

<p>This version fixes a bug with pessimistic matching, adds more tests, improves the documentation with an expanded <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/blob/master/README.md">README</a> and <a href="http://godoc.org/github.com/ctdk/goiardi">more godocs</a>, and introduces client/user authentication and authorization and SSL for connections as optional settings. It will also run and authenticate properly with the chef webui, if you&rsquo;re so inclined. The webui is a separate install, however, and does not ship with goiardi.</p>

<p>There is also a <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/chef-pedant">fork of chef-pedant</a> customized for goiardi now, to handle some tests with authentication where goiardi and the chef-server make slightly different decisions.</p>

<p>Goiardi still works fine in no-auth mode. The authentication and authorization parts are completely optional, but they&rsquo;re there if you want or need authentication. It&rsquo;s recommended that if you do use authentication that you should set the <tt>&mdash;index-file</tt> and <tt>&mdash;data-file</tt> options for persistent data and index storage, but it&rsquo;s not strictly necessary. See the <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/blob/master/README.md">README</a> for more on how to set up authentication.</p>

<p>SSL is pretty straightforward, and also explained in the README. You&rsquo;ll need to <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/10175812/how-to-build-a-self-signed-certificate-with-openssl">generate a certificate/key pair</a> for it to work, but that isn&rsquo;t too hard. This does assume that you&rsquo;d use a self-signed certificate for this; if you&rsquo;re going to use a real cert I assume you know what you&rsquo;re doing (and am a little surprised, to be honest).</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s it for this release. The next major goiardi task coming up, barring any unexpected changes, is allowing it to use a database for the backend. This will be optional, of course; I plan on supporting the in-memory, no-auth mode a la chef-zero for goiardi indefinitely. Further out, there may be a smoother installation process, and someday even perhaps goiardi-specific features.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meanwhile, in the Auth Branch...]]></title>
    <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/03/13/meanwhile-in-the-auth-branch/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-13T10:03:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/03/13/meanwhile-in-the-auth-branch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While there is still some work remaining with finishing some needed authorization checks, I&rsquo;m happy to report that in the <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/tree/auth">goiardi auth branch</a>, authentication for chef clients and webui is working and passing the chef-pedant tests.</p>

<p>Once those authorization issues are ironed out, I&rsquo;ll start work on updating the documentation and making a new formal release. If, in the meantime, anyone felt like testing it, it&rsquo;s pretty easy. Start goiardi with the <tt>-A</tt> or <tt>--use-auth</tt> flags, and set <tt>--conf-root</tt> to whereever you&rsquo;d like the chef-validator, chef-webui, and admin certificates to be stored. You&rsquo;d probably also want to specify index and data files for persistence, but you don&rsquo;t have to. Goiardi works with chef-webui fine as well, but at the moment you&rsquo;ll have to set a password for the admin user with knife.</p>

<p>As of this writing goiardi authentication is still a work in progress, but it&rsquo;s far enough along to start banging on to look for problems. The chef-pedant tests are pretty happy, but that doesn&rsquo;t always catch every real world issue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
