<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Authentication | Goiardi]]></title>
  <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/categories/authentication/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-15T00:52:30-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jeremy Bingham]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meanwhile, in the Auth Branch...]]></title>
    <link href="http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/03/13/meanwhile-in-the-auth-branch/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-13T10:03:30-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://ctdk.github.io/goiardi/blog/2014/03/13/meanwhile-in-the-auth-branch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While there is still some work remaining with finishing some needed authorization checks, I&rsquo;m happy to report that in the <a href="https://github.com/ctdk/goiardi/tree/auth">goiardi auth branch</a>, authentication for chef clients and webui is working and passing the chef-pedant tests.</p>

<p>Once those authorization issues are ironed out, I&rsquo;ll start work on updating the documentation and making a new formal release. If, in the meantime, anyone felt like testing it, it&rsquo;s pretty easy. Start goiardi with the <tt>-A</tt> or <tt>--use-auth</tt> flags, and set <tt>--conf-root</tt> to whereever you&rsquo;d like the chef-validator, chef-webui, and admin certificates to be stored. You&rsquo;d probably also want to specify index and data files for persistence, but you don&rsquo;t have to. Goiardi works with chef-webui fine as well, but at the moment you&rsquo;ll have to set a password for the admin user with knife.</p>

<p>As of this writing goiardi authentication is still a work in progress, but it&rsquo;s far enough along to start banging on to look for problems. The chef-pedant tests are pretty happy, but that doesn&rsquo;t always catch every real world issue.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
